# YOGESWARAN NARASINGAM

No.66, Jalan Jentayu 3, Taman Thivy Jaya 70100 Seremban, Negeri Sembilan

Hp: 0143674658

Resident No: 06-6332453 Email: yogen85@gmail.com



#### **Profile**

Reliable, co-operative and trustworthy. Committed and goal oriented. Self-motivated, passionate and always willing to learn and improve.

# **Executive Summary**

A flexible professional who enjoys learning new skills and quickly adapts to organizational changes. Able to communicate effectively with people of all ages and backgrounds and to work collaboratively to resolve problems. Two years of experience in the Waste Water industry; able to analyze and identify future trends, and market packages to clients and prospects. Experienced with government regulations and compliance issues for handling performance monitoring of Industrial Effluent Treatment System.

### **Academic Qualifications:**

2011 Bachelor of Engineering (Hons)

University Tenaga Nasional

Majoring in Mechanical Engineering

- Relevant subjects: Non- Destructive Testing, Project Management ,Fluids Mechanics , Measurement and instrumentation
- Final Year project: Influence of (Mg-Zn) Additive on the Properties of Hydroxyapatite Ceramics (Predominantly Research Based Project)

2005 Foundation in Engineering

**University Tenaga Nasional** 

### **Professional Qualifications:**

2009 Certificate Program for Engineer

Lembaga Pembangunan Industry Pembinaan Malaysia

Completed

2011 Course for Basic Non Destructive Testing Methods

(PT/MT/UT/RT)

TNB Integrated Learning Solution (ILSAS)

Completed

### **Work Experience:**

May 2012- Present

### Sigma Water Engineering Sdn Bhd

Project/Testing & Commissioning Engineer

Effluent treatment system whereas chemical treatment, dissolved air flotation (DAF) clarification, roughing filter – membrane bio reactor (RF-MBR) biological treatment at Dan Kaffe (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd, Johor (Apr 2013 to Present)

#### Responsibilities and duties:

- Responsible for project planning, execution and handling client meetings/discussions.
- Responsible to prepare project man-hour estimation, technical and costing analysis/reports.
- Provide weekly and monthly project reports to management, client and Dept of Environment.
- Involved in the mechanical design activities including systems design, pipe sizing based on fluid mechanics, pump matching to system, selection and use of piping components, pipe routing and pipe support.
- Liaises with Project Manager on technical matters and plan co-ordinates site activities.
- Liaison with internal department (Marketing & Engineering Dept), consultant and contractor/sub-contractor on technical/site matters.
- Prepares general site administration work, site daily reports and reporting monthly work progress.
- Attending site meeting and coordinating site activities.
- Monitors work progress and quality controls are complied with the procedures.

Effluent treatment system whereas chemical treatment, dissolved air flotation (DAF) clarification, roughing filter – membrane bio reactor (RF-MBR) biological treatment at Super Food Specialists (M) Sdn Bhd, Johor (Apr 2013 to August 2013)

### Responsibilities and duties:

- -Preparation of site planning/ Co-ordination and Material Requisition
- Conduct the outstanding work at site.
- Closely monitor the biological progress at site.
- Updating the Operational and Manual to the client
- -To provide training for the operator to operate the plant at desired output.

Design, Supply, Fabrication, Construction, Delivery to Site, Installation, completion, Testing, Commissioning And Guarantee the Performance Of Tertiary Effluent Treatment Plant at Semenchu Palm Oil Mill, Kota Tinggi, Johor (Jun 2012 to July 2013)

#### Responsibilities and duties:

- Preparation of site planning/ Co-ordination and Material Requisition
- Attend all site meeting.
- Project Preliminaries preparation & project acceptance.
- Daily & monthly work progress report i.e physical and financial data report.
- Testing & Commissioning of the WWTP Plant.
- Ensure/ Enforce safety and accountability for jobsite safety.
- Responsible to prepare project man-hour estimation, technical and costing analysis/reports.

## 2010-2010 Emerson Process Management

**Engineering Intern** 

#### Responsibilities and duties:

- To inspect materials, parts or product according to drawing, specification, standard and customer requirements
- Expose to in manufacturing and/ or quality assurance/ quality control.
- Exposed on the products that has been manufactured such as piston, valves and actuators.
- Preparing incoming material & Defect report.
- Conduct product test before handing over to the production line.

## **Language Proficiency:**

Malay: Fluent and Spoken Written English: Fluent and Spoken Written

Tamil: Mother Tongue

#### Other Details:

Willing To Travel :Yes Marital Status :Single

Date of Availability :Immediate after notice period of 1 month

Possesses Own Transport :Yes

## **References:**

Ir.Dr. Anand Exec Director Sigma Water Engineering Sdn Bhd (HP Phone No) 60173339070 Ir.Dr.Azmi Bin Ahmad Principal Research TNB TNB Research Sdn Bhd (HP Phone No) 019-2579382